Give Sarah my love.
...multiple lacerations.
My daughter, she's five years old.
Hey.
It's okay. You're in the hospital.
Are you in pain?
We can give you something.
Ellie!
Here.
It's okay.
And how would you rate your pain? Scale of one to ten?
Nothing. Zero.
Zero. Can't ask for much more than that.
Okay. One last PFT.
Look at that.
Yeah.
Alright. Today's the day.
- So, can I just-- - Almost.
I just need you to see one more person, then you're good to go.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
- How are you doing? - Fine.
If you say it that fast, it kind of implies you're not.
Okay, ask me again.
How are you doing, Ellie?
Give me a moment. It's really complicated 'cause, you know, feelings.
Okay.
Oh, come on, man, I've been stuck in here since...
Yeah, I miss him. He meant a lot to me. So, yeah. Upset and sad.
Of course.
But I was actually wondering about New Year's Eve.
You two got into it at the dance. Was that the last time you spoke to him?
Yeah.
When I got home, he was on the porch,
and I should've talked to him, but I didn't.
- Do you regret that? - Yeah, of course.
But your final moment with someone
doesn't define your whole time with them.
It shouldn't, but it often does.
In my last moment with Joel, he said he
wronged you.
Maybe bad.
What is it that he said that he did?
Well, that's the thing. It didn't really make sense.
He said, "I saved her."
He saved me a lot of times.
Yeah, I would think so. But that's not wronging someone.
That's weird.
No idea what he meant.
I don't feel wronged.
Man, I wish I could have let him off the hook for whatever it was he was talking about.
I guess I'll have to let myself off the hook for that.
Well, you really are doing good.
Shit,
if everyone were as healthy as you, what would I do for weed and booze?
I wouldn't worry, Gail, there's still a lot of fucked up people in this town.
Yeah. But not you, though.
Ellie?
Fuck.
Yeah, I'm coming.
I went to the hospital.
When'd they let you out?
- Thirty minutes ago. - Nice.
They made me talk to Gail.
I never said--
I should have said thank you for all those times you came to visit.
That's okay. You would have done the same for me.
- Yeah, maybe not as often. - Yeah, no, probably not.
I made you cookies.
Just 'cause?
This is a peace offering.
Because I'm about to make you angry.
In the hospital,
when you asked me
about that day,
I told you I didn't learn anything useful.
That wasn't true.
I know most of their names, and I know where they're from.
Please, just listen.
- The doctors told me not to upset you. - I don't give a fuck.
And I knew that if I told you where they were, you'd just start pulling your tubes out
and crawling on your hands and knees to get there.
I don't give a fuck.
You cost us time. You let them get away.
First of all,
this town was wreckage and funerals for weeks.
Nobody was gonna go after anyone.
And then it occurred to me, if you wanna find someone,
and the only thing you know about them is where they're gonna end up.
Maybe let them get there.
I loved him too, you know.
Okay, let's start with names.
The dark-haired guy was Manny. The other guy was Owen.
The girl with the dark hair and the bald one, one of them's named Nora.
- I'm not sure which. - The girl with the braid?
Abby.
Where are they from?
I saw a patch on a backpack.
Yellow triangle, wolf's head,
and the letters W-L-F.
And then, I remembered a story Eugene told me from back when he was a Firefly.
He said that there were these small regional groups in the West all trying to fight FEDRA,
and how stupid it was that they didn't just join together.
One of those groups was the Washington Liberation Front.
Out of Seattle.
W-L-F. Wolf.
Fucking morons.
- Did he say how small they were? - No.
But seeing as how no one's ever mentioned them since,
I'm guessing small enough for us to handle.
Who else knows?
Just us.
I wasn't gonna tell anyone before you.
So, now what?
Well?
I gotta think about this.
Think about what? Let's fucking get these guys.
Ellie, it ain't that simple.
The town is still recovering. So are you.
- We get where you're coming from-- - No, we don't get where you're coming from.
I don't get where you're coming from. If it had been you, Joel would be halfway to Seattle before the sun came up.
He'd be halfway to Seattle to save my life.
But when we lost people, no.
It would just break him like it was his fault.
I saw that time and time again. And don't talk to me like I didn't know him.
He was my brother.
Listen, I'm not sayin' you shouldn't do this.
But if we're gonna put a posse together, we gotta do it right,
which means taking it to Maria. Yes, it's fuckin' necessary.
She's gonna want a council meeting, open it up to the town.
Everyone who wants to get heard gets heard.
But you'll back us, right?
Of course, I will.
Come here.
And you,
you hold out information on me again, you got rendering detail for a month.
Alright.
Ellie.
We buried our dead ten miles south of town.
If you want to visit him.
When we're on our way to Seattle.
Well?
"No one following. All clear. Keep moving."
Good.
Once we get resettled, I'll teach you to whistle.
Why can't you tell me where we're going?
'Cause we don't know yet.
I've told you the reason we're going.
I know, but why can't she just keep us safe?
The Prophet?
She's been dead ten years, Constance. I wouldn't count on her to help.
But Ezra said the Prophet is eternal.
Well, she is, in a way.
A prophet isn't magic.
They're just
people that see truths hidden from others
and share that truth, no matter what the cost.
So it was with our Prophet.
So it was.
That's how we keep her spirit alive.
Follow her words, we obey her teachings, but we keep ourselves safe.
Then, can I have a hammer?
Alright.
Tell me, you feel safer?
Yes.
Good.
Understand, what we're giving you now,
will keep you far, far safer than a hammer.
Distance.
From home.
From war.
Take cover! Go!
Demons?
Wolves.
Alright. Good, but rotate. More.
Now, the right side. Just the right side.
- Come on, man, that side hurts more. - I noticed.
- Come on. - Okay.
Harder. Harder! Let's go! Last five.
- There it is, okay. Done for the day. - Okay.
So, what'd you think?
Well, for someone who sat on their ass for three months,
- I'm pleasantly surprised. - Yeah?
Push-ups?
Yeah, and crunches when they weren't looking.
Yeah, that'll do it. A few more weeks, and you'll be right back to where you were before.
Nice.
- Which is 80% of where you should have been. - Whatever. Fuck you.
So, I heard you're on the council now.
Yep.
So, you know about the meeting coming up?
I know about the meeting coming up.
Can I count on you?
I can't discuss upcoming votes.
- Seriously? It's me. - I know.
Dude, you were there.
I know that too.
Gotta go.
Oh, my God.
Ellie.
The council won't make up their mind until we hear people speak.
So, here's a little advice.
Organize your thoughts, write them down, and then read 'em out loud tomorrow.
- Okay, yeah, 'cause I'm stupid. - 'Cause you're angry, Ellie.
And no one's gonna vote for angry.
Which is why I keep saying we need to invest more in turkeys
and less in chickens.
And that brings me back to my earlier point about corn.
Corn, some of you have heard me say, is not the easiest crop to grow,
but it is among the fastest.
You can plot a graph that shows ease and resources versus time to harvest and get a li--
Scott, I'm sorry, but we gotta keep you on target here.
But it's an open meeting. The bylaws say that--
Maybe we should stick to what everyone else came here to discuss.
I don't really have an opinion on the Seattle thing.
Okay. Thank you.
So, that was Scott. Next is Rachel.
Yeah, Joel meant so much to so many of us.
Can't hear you.
- Can you take him, please? - Yeah.
Okay, here we go.
I said that Joel meant so much to so many of us.
But he wasn't the only one.
I lost my sister that day.
A lot of people in here buried family.
And now, you wanna send, what, you're saying 16 of our best?
Well, while they're gone, who's gonna be on the wall if Raiders come?
A wall that's barely mended.
And none of you up there can promise us that all 16 will come back.
So, my heart is with you, Tommy and Ellie.
We are too hurt, and it is too soon.
Thank you, Rachel.
Next is Carlisle.
I'll be quick. 'Cause this one's simple to me.
People came
and killed Joel.
So, why wouldn't we wanna take our vengeance?
Well, because we're not supposed to.
Forgive and be forgiven.
No grudges. No revenge.
And I'm not even a Christian. I've always seen the wisdom in that.
That's what separates us from the Raiders and the murderers.
Our capacity for mercy.
Those sons of bitches don't deserve our mercy.
Well, of course they don't deserve it.
That's what makes it mercy.
Well, to hell with that. And to hell with you for saying it, Carlisle.
- Seth, sit down. - No.
- You're not on the list. - No!
What the hell are we all talking about here?
It's not fair.
What, we gotta forgive everybody when they show up and piss in our eye?
They came into our house.
They took one of ours.
My God,
somebody shoots your brother, you wanna take the locks off your doors?
Grow up!
You idiots, they'll come back.
They'll come back because we didn't make 'em pay.
And when they come back, they'll be laughing.
And you'll all deserve it.
Bunch of
goddamn victims.
Ellie?
I normally don't write things down
because I normally don't think before I talk,
which has gotten me in trouble before, a lot,
and it's cost me in ways that sometimes couldn't be undone.
But I can't afford that right now, because I know what I'm asking is a lot.
I'm asking us to risk more people and resources,
and at the worst possible time.
And I want everyone to know, it's not because I want revenge.
It's not. It's not about revenge.
What I want is what you used to give people.
I want justice.
Because it's either that, or we do nothing.
That's what everyone else out there is going to do for us.
Nothing. A whole world of people who won't lift a finger
if something bad happens to me or you.
We have a word for these people.
They're called strangers.
Well, I don't think that we're strangers to each other.
And I want to know that I can count on you.
And I swear, if someone hurts any of you or the people you love,
you can count on me.
That's what holds all this together.
Not potluck dinners or New Year's Eve dances.
Definitely not a wall, because that thing got busted through.
But Jackson is still here.
I'll accept whatever the council decides.
But I am asking you, please,
do what it takes to see that justice is done.
Not for me.
Not even for Joel.
I am asking you, please, do it for us.
Thank you.
The council will now vote on the proposal to send a party of 16 citizens to Seattle
to find the people who killed Joel and execute them.
Amy-Beth?
Yes.
No.
The vote is 8 to 3. The proposal is rejected.
Adjourned.
Here we go, nine. Here we go.
Grab the ball!
Attaboy, nine!
Oh, shit.
I didn't know you were a fan.
Hell, yeah! I had Tigers season tickets.
This actually isn't that far off from the '03 squad.
You want a beer? I get them from Marshall.
I spotted you in the crowd at the meeting today.
Yeah.
And I thought to myself,
she's probably been extra busy these last few weeks.
Brutal.
And I'm supposed to see a shrink myself, you know, to process it all, it's...
I'm the only one here.
- So, what do you do, then? - Oh, well, I'm an alcoholic.
And I smoke as much weed as I can.
You know, complete fuckin' disaster.
But you're not here 'cause you're worried about me.
Two outs, guys, two outs. Look alive!
I don't know.
You see things that others don't.
I'm nervous she's gonna do somethin' stupid.
- What, you didn't believe her speech? - Did you?
Course not. She's a liar.
Well, there's a difference between lyin' and being a liar.
Oh, I know. And that one? Liar.
There was maybe one person she told the truth to, and he's...
But we can agree to disagree about that.
What matters is you're afraid. So, let's talk about it.
Okay. Free of charge.
I just don't want her to go down the same paths that Joel did.
Comin' up with justifications and such.
All he was really doin' was lashin' out.
So, you think she might have learned that behavior from him?
Turns out nurture can only do this much. The rest is nature.
If she's on a path, it's not one that Joel put her on.
No. No.
I think they were walking side by side from the very start.
Tommy, I get it.
You inherited her, and you wanna keep her out of trouble.
Take it from a psychotherapist of 40 years.
Some people just...
Some people just can't be saved.
- Who is it? - Dina.
Hey.
I'm just going to bed.
No, I don't think that is where you're going.
Are you alone?
I'm alone.
Get in.
Oh, Christ.
- Please don't try and talk me out of this. - You think that's why I'm here?
So, what's your plan?
Go to Seattle and kill Abby.
What route?
Northwest.
And is that all guns, or do you have medical supplies in there? No?
Well, better not land weird on an ankle
or get a fever on your well-charted path "northwest."
Okay, so what am I supposed to do?
Stay off the highways. Steer clear of cities or settlements.
First stage is through the national forest.
Once we're out, we follow the Snake River Canyon,
- then break off through the Snoqualmie Pass. - Snoqualmie?
Yeah. Snoqualmie.
Approach Seattle from the east, then reassess based on what we find.
Provisions. Travel light, but smart.
Winter coats for beds, jackets for blankets.
First aid kits, batteries, bear spray. Now, handguns. What are you bringing?
Is that Joel's?
So, that's what you're gonna kill her with?
- Fuckin' right. - Then, save it for that.
It's slow and kicks like hell.
Really? Shoot your damn ass off?
I've heard that before.
We'll want at least 100 shells apiece, plus 50 rifle rounds.
Bring any long gun you want, as long as it's scoped.
Chlorine tablets, a pan, and something to keep Shimmer dry.
- Just Shimmer? - Yeah.
We share a horse. Fewer resources.
Everything else is what you'd figure, except this.
Boots.
Love the Converse. Respect your consistency.
But you're not crossing open country in fuckin' Chucks.
- I've done it before. - No Chucks. Questions?
Yeah, one. How the fuck are we gonna get all of this?
I know a guy.
Oh, no. No, don't tell me you told Jesse, please.
Captain Wyoming? No.
I love the man, but he's a little uptight about rules and shit.
Wear all the clothes you're gonna bring, fill your pockets with ammo.
Everything else needs to fit inside a holster or your backpack.
We'll meet by the old east gate, 3:00 a.m.
3:00 a.m.
Hey.
Thank you.
You know, you could have just asked.
No, I actually didn't know that.
Now you do.
Trade.
It's better. Trade.
How'd you get her out?
Jeanine's night watch at the stables. She's sympathetic to our cause.
"Our cause"?
You're the one that gave the "us" speech, not me.
Saddlebags are filled with stuff I had squirreled away.
Two weeks' worth of hardtack, bandages, alcohol, meds, batteries.
I'd come with you, but I caught some friendly fire on New Year's Day.
- You sure it was friendly? - Jesus Christ.
We got ten minutes before a patrol comes by. Let's get you going.
Okay, so...F.
F. Fleetwood Mac.
- Nope. - What?
What do you mean, "no"? It's my opinion.
Yeah, well, your opinion is wrong because Frank Zappa exists.
Okay, so, G.
- Green Day. - No, you're wrong. It's Guns N' Roses.
Ozzy Osbourne.
Nice! Double points.
L M N O P
So, L-M-N-O, P.
Are you seriously gonna make me do the entire alphabet?
We don't have to. I'm incredibly flexible. Lemme see, new topic.
- Or silence. - Got one. First person you killed.
Jesus, really?
Yeah, fun stories of childhood.
Okay, well, the first one's too fucked up, but I can tell you the second one.
I accept.
It was a little before Joel and I got to Jackson.
In Kansas City, he got jumped by this kid, maybe just a couple years older than me.
And I came up behind him, raised my gun and, yeah.
Sorry, Ellie.
Interesting. I shoot a guy, and you feel sorry for me?
I'm just loyal like that.
Let me know if you see any outcroppings or spots with cover.
Why? It looks okay.
Holy shit, that came on fast. How the fuck did you know that was gonna happen?
- I'm a witch. - Clearly.
Well, good night.
Night.
Okay, but I have a stupid question.
It's about New Year's Eve, and, you know,
the kiss.
Okay. I mean, whatever, you were super high.
And you were drunk.
Right, so it doesn't mean anything, if that's what you're asking.
No, I know that. My question is,
how would you rate it?
- Scale of one to ten. - No.
Come on. You've kissed girls before.
You're gay, I'm not.
I'm just curious. I wanna know if I'm any good at it.
One to ten.
Okay, fine. Six.
- Fuck you, "six." - That's not bad.
That sucks!
What?
For the record, I don't believe you.
Well, you asked, and I told you. I'm sorry.
You can go back to Jesse.
I already did.
Well, there you have it.
Does he ever strike you as sad?
Jesse? Yeah.
Has he ever told you why?
No.
But I think deep inside, that's just how he is.
- At least, I hope that's why. - Why would you hope that?
Well, because if it's not that,
then it's me.
Well, good night.
Night.
Ellie?
I wasn't that high.
How much further?
Close.
Maybe ten miles?
In theory, we'll come out near Highway Five, just north of the city.
He was running away.
What's that symbol?
I don't know, I've never seen it before.
A lot of different calibers. I don't think this was FEDRA.
Dina.
Dina?
- You okay? - It's just...
Doing okay?
Yeah, I'm sorry, it's just that's never happened before.
- I think it was the smell. - It wasn't easy to look at either.
If this was fucking them,
if Abby and her crew did this to people,
to kids?
Yeah.
Let's go.
We're close now.
It's quiet.
Yeah. Too quiet.
Curtis or Viper?
Both, in all four movies.
Nine more miles.
Nine more.
Fucking Seattle. Pretty.
Plus, no one's shooting at us.
I guess there aren't that many Wolves.
There's about to be a whole lot less.
- Curtis or Viper? - What?
No, that was just me. I was trying to sound like a badass.
You don't need to try.
Manny.
Yeah, go ahead.
We're moving up to the FOB. All clear between checkpoint three and five?
Told me to watch six and eight. Now, they want fuckin' three and five.
Manny, you copy?
Just give me a fuckin' second. Jesus.
You're all good. You can move up.